在我们继续学习和创建一个ContentProvider之前
Before we go ahead and build a content provider
你会不会想到去问，这是为什么呢？
you wouldn't be out of line to ask, well why.
最简单的答案就是ContentProvider允许你
The simplest answer is that it allows you to
安全并且高效地跨过应用程序的界限分享你的数据
share your data safely and efficiently across app boundaries by
而这需要你把底层数据源做一定的抽象，就像你使用SQLite
abstracting the underlying data source, be it SQLite like
或者文件，或者其他的什么东西。然后其他
this or files or really anything else. So that other
应用便可以访问它，而不需要真正理解你是如何存储它的
apps can access it without really needing to understand how
事实上，日历，短信和联系人
you stored it. In fact, the calendar, SMS, and contacts
的API都是用shared content providers这种方法工作的
APIs work that way, using shared content providers.
我们等会将要分享我们的天气数据库，但是如果
We're going to share our weather database later, but if
你不想公开你的应用的数据
you're not planning to expose your app's data, you're
你可能会考虑跳过这个步骤，对吧？
probably thinking you can skip this bit, right? Well,
但实际上，在很多时候你可以这样做
almost, in a lot of cases you could,
但你不应该这样做。比如说，在Sunshine这个应用中，我们使用
but really shouldn't. For example, in Sunshine we're using
SQLite。但是你可以将数据存储在文件中
SQ Lite. But you could be storing data in
动态的运行时数据中，或者也可能只是一个不同的数据库中
files, dynamic run-time data or even just a different
通过使用ContentProvider，使你更加容易
database library. By using content providers, it's easier for
将数据源切换成另一个
you to potentially switch out the data source and
并且能使别人比你更容易去管理
much easier for someone other than you to manage
UI层的代码，即使他们并没有深入理解
the UI layer code without them having to understand
你的数据存储是怎样实现的。
the depths of your data storage implementation. On the
在UI层，这是一个通用的返回光标机制
UI layer, it's a generic mechanism that returns cursors.
就和SQLite 数据库中返回数据一样
The same of those returned by SQLite databases. So,
所以，如果你的数据层实现有改变，你的ContentProvider
if your data layer implementation changes, then your content provider
会受到影响。现在是你该写代码的时候了
is effected. Still, it's just you writing the code right
这么多的例子是为了顺应
now and that's a lot of boilerplate for the sake of
简洁的设计模式。嗯，记住
following a neat design pattern. Well, keep in mind that
就framework而言，所有的数据都通过ContentProvider处理
as far as the framework is concerned, all data is handled
所以，如果你要和你的应用外的
through content providers. So, if you want to interact with
任何东西互动，比如说，向widget发送数据
anything outside of your app, such as sending data to a
或者从新的应用那里返回搜索结果
widget or returning search results from the newer app, you'll need
你会需要一个ContentProvider去做这些事情。事实上，这就是
a content provider for that too. In fact, that's how the
Google play store 和Gmail widgets 的工作方式，以及
Google play store and Gmail widgets work. As well as the
为什么能够从Google Play得到搜索结果。同样的，这里有一堆API
ability to get search results from Google Play. Similarly, there's a bunch
旨在优化 同步，查询数据 和
of APIs designed to optimize the process of synching and querying data,
更新相应的UI。这些都期待用ContentProvider实现
and updating UI accordingly. And all of them also expect content providers.
这些(优化用的API)包括了SyncAdapter和CursorLoader，它们使得
That includes sync adapters and cursor loaders. Which make your
你的应用可以和服务端有效地进行同步，可以从UI层载入数据
app able to efficiently sync with your server, load data in
还包括了内置的content observers 即当你的基础数据发生改变时
your UI layer, and which include built in content observers that
它们将会自动更新你的UI
will update your UI automatically when the underlying data changes. You
你当然可以自己将这些全部建立起来
could, of course, build all of that yourself but at
但从某种程度来说
a certain point the advantage you gained by not writing a
你所获得的优势是通过一开始不写ContentProvider
content provider to begin with is lost in the process of
而丢失不必重新创建所有使用它的有用簇的过程
having to recreate all of the useful clusters that utilize it.
在这节课的后面，我们将会看一下你发布的ContentProvider并使用Lotus
We'll take a look at publishing your content provider and using Lotus
去有效地访问它。在第六节课程中，当我们做有效的背景更新时，
to access it efficiently later in this lesson. And we'll explore sync adapters
我们还会探索sync adapter
in lesson six when we look at doing efficient background updates. But
但首先，Dan已经准备好向你展示如何建立一个ContentProvider了
first, Dan is going to show you how to actually build a content provider.